D'VONTRAY: Deep-fried shrimp.
And lobster.
I never had lobster.
What, do they boil them
or grill them?
Which one's better?
Just get them both.
And I know I need
a strawberry malt.
And then there's those
chocolate donuts,
they come in a box.
WARDEN: We'll do our best to
accommodate. Tomorrow you'll
be moved to a holding cell.
That's where
you'll get your last meal.
You also have a constitutional
right to a spiritual advisor
of your choice.
No, I don't need none of that.
One last thing to think about.
After I read
the execution warrant,
you'll be given an opportunity
to make a statement.
You might wanna take some time
and think about
what you wanna say
as your final words.
D'VONTRAY: Yo, Clarence!
You hear that?
(CHUCKLES)
A spiritual advisor
of my choice.
Don't matter,
you're going to hell anyway.
You think
I'll get another stay?
You should.
Supreme Court said it ain't
right to kill retards.
GUARD: Cut the chatter!
Exercise time.
(SlGHS)
Be back in an hour. Enjoy.
(BREATHlNG HEAVlLY)
Huh? What?
Why did you hit me
so many times, Clarence?
You know why!
You could have stopped.
You stabbed me
in the back, man.
Look, I never...
You couldn't fight fair?
Like you did?
I had a wife and three kids.
You were a sick bastard!
Open the door! Open the door!
Clarence!
What'd I ever do to you, man?
CARLOS: You better stay
in this place.
EMMlTT: I was just minding
my own business.
(VOlCES CHATTERlNG)
(GASPlNG)
(WOMAN CHATTERINN
ON P.A. SYSTEM)
You can't go in there.
Who are you?
And why are you wearing a tie?
I'm Dr. Cuddy's new assistant.
Can I tell her
what it's regarding?
Yes. I would like to know
why she gets a secretary
and I don't.
I'm her assistant,
not her secretary.
I graduated from Rutgers.
I didn't know
they had a secretarial school.
Well,
I hope you took some classes
in sexual harassment law.
Does the word "ka-ching"
mean anything to you?
I'm going in now.
Dr. House, we are
in the middle of a meeting.
What's with hiring
a male secretary?
J-Date not working out?
He is cute, be careful.
She's not like you,
she can't just walk into a bar
and pick up her soul mate
in 20 minutes.
I met Mark at a fundraiser
that happened
to be held at a...
You met me at a strip club.
You were the worst $2
I've ever spent.
We'll catch up later.
Stacy, it's House.
I know you can handle it.
Nothing to handle.
He obviously wants
to talk to you alone.
CUDDY: If you have a problem
working with Stacy,
you should have said so.
What was I supposed to do?
Ask her to leave?
That's just rude.
Death row guy.
I want the case.
How do you even
know about him?
You don't have access
to the hospital's mainframe.
No, but Party-Pants does.
You stole my password?
Hardly counts as stealing,
it's a pretty obvious choice.
Well, I have already assigned
"death row guy" to Dr. Nolo.
Nolo? Well, l...
I don't wanna say anything bad
about another doctor,
especially a useless drunk.
You are addicted
to pain pills.
Yeah, but I'm not useless.
Tell Nolo I'm taking over.
Dr. Nolo is a
board-certified cardiologist.
Well, good.
I'm sure he'll explore
all the usual options
for why a guy's heart starts
beating so fast it pumps out
air instead of blood.
Wait a second.
There are no usual options.
How badly do you want this?
I will give you two more
clinic hours this week.
Don't bend over for the soap.
Just the heart,
or the patient have
any other complaints?
Patient's not talking
to anybody.
Where are we going?
You are going
to the clinic for two hours.
Me? Why?
Talk to Cuddy.
She's got me going
to Mercer State Prison,
Capital Sentences Unit.
Aren't there better ways
to spend our time?
Good question.
What makes a person deserving?
Is a man
who cheats on his wife
more deserving than a man
who kills his wife?
Yeah, actually, he is.
What about a child molester?
Certainly not a good guy,
but he didn't kill anybody.
Maybe he can get
antibiotics, but no MRls.
What about you?
What medical care
should you be denied
for being a car thief?
Tell you what.
Three of you work on a list
of what medical treatments
a person loses based on
the crime they committed.
I'll review it
when I get back.
Your patient
shanked one inmate
his first month here.
Broke another one's neck.
Nearly decapitated
one of my guards.
Relax. I got
a great bedside manner.
Too dangerous to house him
in the infirmary.
You don't have to worry,
we've taken every precaution.
I've had my men clear
from the cell all pens,
paper clips, and staplers.
Any supplies that might
be used as a weapon.
Open her up!
(KEYS RATTLlNG)
WARDEN: For your visit,
we've got him cuffed
and shackled.
And yet you're
staying out there.
You're gonna have
to give me that. Wouldn't
want anybody to get hurt.
Hi.
I'm Dr. Cameron.
How you feeling?
Little cough, no big deal.
Okay,
then what you doing here?
I just got a job
at the university,
they need a health clearance.
Apparently,
I'm a little anemic, so they
made me get some more tests.
Any family history of anemia?
Not that I know of.
My mom died of cancer
when I was a kid.
My dad's heart gave out
a couple of years ago.
Brothers and sisters?
I'm afraid it's a short
family history. That's it.
I had a husband once,
but it didn't stick.
My tests should be back,
probably in that file.
Probably.
Yeah.
Is everything okay?
WlLSON: Did you redo
the x-ray?
Twice.
Well,
you don't need a consult.
You know the diagnosis.
All she has is a cough.
Bluish tinge
to the fingernails. Lips.
He's hypoxic.
What's that mean?
It means he's not
getting enough oxygen.
You know how people say
you can't live without love?
Well,
oxygen's even more important.
(GASPlNG)
He's got fluid in his lungs.
Breathing rate of 50.
He needs to be intubated,
put on a respirator.
Don't have a respirator.
Better get one
in about an hour,
or you're gonna lose him.
I'll make out a requisition.
State's already sentenced
this man to die.
I think the state was
a tad more specific about how.
This is Dr. Gregory House.
I need an ambulance pick-up
at Mercer State Prison.
Wasted call, my men will
stop them at the gate.
No way a death row inmate
leaves my prison.
At least,
not through the front doors.
You work fast.
So do you.
Was that a shot?
Yeah.
It was easy,
once I convinced the clerk
to take it to Judge Markham.
She's a sucker for
Eighth Amendment arguments.
Stop, I'm getting turned on.
House!
It was just a consult!
You expect us to shut down
an entire floor for this guy?
Did you do
something to your hair?
Stacy!
You said
you cleared it with her!
Come on,
you've known me how long?
And you still can't tell
when I'm joshing you?
Take him back to prison. Now.
No, can't.
See, ironically,
I'm bound by this court order
that your ace attorney got.
I have to make him all better
before shipping him back
for the state to kill him.
Is it just me,
or is that weird?
Anyway, we're walking.
(SlGHlNG)
Somebody left this
on my chair.
It's clever, 'cause it forces
me to either deal with the
file or never sit down again.
Cindy Kramer.
I told her you'd see her.
Well, you shouldn't
have told her that.
She's got metastatic squamous
cell lung cancer.
Six months tops.
Have you even looked
at the x-ray?
No. Just guessing.
It's a new game. If I'm wrong,
she wins a stuffed bear.
A spot on an x-ray
doesn't necessarily mean
that she's terminal.
I love children.
So filled with hope.
It could be pneumonia.
It could be sarcoidosis.
Could be. If she didn't
already have swollen hilar
lymph nodes on the other lung.
Can we at least
brainstorm for other ideas?
(SlGHlNG)
Thank you.
I still think
pneumonia and sarcoidosis.
But, we should check
for tuberculosis
and definitely rule out
congestive heart failure.
Five stages of dying.
Exactly.
Personally, I think
it's all just New Age crap,
but from your tear-filled,
puppy dog eyes,
I think I've made my point.
Now go tell Cindy
whatever-her-name-is
that she's dying.
Tachycardia. Pulmonary edema.
Likely suspects?
The death row guy?
That's who you're working on
instead of Cindy?
God, I've got to learn
not to beat around the bush.
By "dying," I meant
no matter what we do.
Very, very soon
she is going to be dead.
Is that still too subtle?
I took an oath
to "do no harm."
Yeah, but it's not like
they make you
sign it or anything.
We cure your patient,
he goes back to death row.
He goes back to death row,
they kill him.
He stays here and we don't
treat him, he dies.
And I still don't treat
"Cindy Lou Who."
Can we get on with this?
Yeah, I knew I could count
on your help for your homie.
Exactly. I'm black.
I sympathize with guys
who grew up in the inner city,
kept down by The Man.
Makes sense to me.
FOREMAN: It's a bunch of crap!
You can't blame society
for the fact that you chose
to become a killer.
The guy's probably
a heroin addict.
That explains the tachycardia,
which caused the
pulmonary edema.
How does an inmate
on death row
get his hands on heroin?
Are you serious?
HOUSE: Man knows prisons.
When we got
a yachting question,
we'll come to you.
Okay, drugs it is.
Test his hair,
blood, urine, works.
Thanks for getting my back.
I thought
you seminary boys were
against the death penalty.
I've left the seminary.
Over their stance
on capital punishment?
I'm against the death penalty
in principle.
In practice, however,
watching a murderer die
causes me
a lot less grief
than annoying my boss.
We gotta check you out
before you go in.
CAMERON: Department of Justice
statistics show
that it's a racially motivated
form of punishment.
Black defendants are 10 times
more likely to get
a death sentence than whites.
Doesn't mean
we need to get rid
of the death penalty.
Just means we need
to kill more white people.
(GRUNTS)
It's okay.
You're in a hospital,
we're taking care of you.
Stay calm, you hear me?
Push two milligrams Ativan!
(GROANlNG)
Water. Water.
What's the differential
for being thirsty?
He was just
a little dehydrated.
And out of his mind.
We upped his saline drip.
He's fine now.
Blood and urine tests
came back clean, no sign
of opiates in his system.
Don't do that.
What?
You have some House theory
explaining heroin use
despite a negative test?
Nope.
Only I get to write
on the board.
So it's not drugs.
What else can cause a heart
to do wind sprints?
You got the blood work back,
anything out of the ordinary?
His bi-carb is low.
Yeah, but which column?
It could be the result
of the tachycardia,
or it could be the cause.
It's the cause.
Why,
because you want it to be?
Let's see how well that works
with your other patient.
We're just talking
semantics here.
We should put him
on a bi-carb drip
and send him back.
Right. Buff his numbers,
don't bother trying to figure
out the underlying cause.
I thought you cared
about patients.
FOREMAN: Our job isn't
to make sure he can bounce
his grandkids on his lap.
Our job is to get him
healthy enough to go back
to death row.
Our job is to diagnose him.
What?
Mommy and Daddy are having
a little fight, doesn't mean
we've stopped loving you.
Now, go outside and play.
Get Daddy some smokes,
and an arterial
blood gas test.
(EXCLAlMlNG)
That was impressive. Okay,
what number am I thinking of?
Are you trying
to get me fired?
If you didn't want me
working here,
why didn't you just say so?
I just don't want you
working right here,
in my office.
But anywhere else
in the building is fine.
Oh.
It's a really big hospital.
I'm a lawyer, you're a jerk.
There's gonna be some overlap.
God, I hope
that was a euphemism.
Cuddy just reamed me!
I hope that one means
what I think it means.
For trusting you.
She figured when she hired me
she'd at least have someone
you couldn't walk all over.
The number was six,
by the way.
I need to know,
can I trust you?
If I hadn't lied to you
about Cuddy's approval,
my patient would be dead.
Great.
Now I know.
Now we can work together.
I'll be drawing some blood
from your femoral artery.
From my what?
Runs through your groin.
You think
you're gonna stick me
in the jewels with that?
It's really closer
to your thigh. Technically
at this point, it seems like
your jewels are more
for display purposes anyway.
Hold up, hold up.
Gimme some painkillers
or something.
A tough guy like you
don't need them.
Forget that, numb me up, man.
You got some gang ink?
Let me see that.
It's a Native American symbol.
It means "the force of life."
That's what you tell
all these white dudes
so they let you play doctor.
Yup, got them all fooled.
For real, how a brother
like you go from gang banging
to wearing that white coat?
How's a brother like you
go from loving a woman
to punching her skull in?
Bitch stepped out.
(SCREAMS)
Sorry about that.
Guess I didn't use
enough lidocaine.
Blood gas came back
with a pH of 7.28,
and decreased HCO-3.
Which means two things.
Most importantly,
Cameron was wrong
about the bi-carb.
And less significantly,
we have a new symptom.
Anion gap acidosis.
Who's chubby? Come on,
pretend he loves puppies.
Pretend he's a human being.
What do you got?
I think we should
reconsider drugs.
He already tested negative.
That's why I said reconsider.
Back in juvie, I cut up
oregano and sold it as pot.
Is that how you put yourself
through med school?
What if Clarence thought
he was taking heroin,
but it was something else?
What "something else"
could lead
to anion gap acidosis?
Mudpiles.
Well, you don't have to ask,
just wash your hands
before you come back.
Methanol, uremia, diabetes...
Oh, it's a mnemonic.
That makes sense, too.
Paraldehyde,
lNH, Lactic acid...
Rewind.
INH?
Yahtzee.
Drugs for tuberculosis.
Nearly a quarter
of the prison population
is infected with TB.
Clever entrepreneur like
Foreman here chops up his
meds, passes it off as heroin.
INH poisoning would explain
all the symptoms.
Who wants to head over
to the prison and find
Clarence's secret stash?
Fine, I'll do it.
Great! Chase it is.
I assume you have a reason
beyond wanting to make me
completely miserable.
You got a prettier mouth.
Better chance the inmates
will open up to you.
JOHN CLlFT: Perhaps
I'll come out
looking just as monstrous.
I mean,
isn't that what I deserve?
Dr. VlVlAN: John,
it wasn't your fault.
If your father hadn't
slipped you those drugs,
you would have never done...
The man's in a coma!
He didn't mind. I asked.
You're getting crumbs
all over him.
Why do you think they put TVs
in coma patients' rooms,
anyway?
Some people think
they can still hear.
Well, so leave them a radio.
His eyes are closed.
Who thinks they can see?
(SLURPlNG)
Do you know why people
are nice to other people?
Oh, I know this one!
Because people are good,
decent and caring.
Either that,
or people are cowards.
If I'm mean to you,
you'll be mean to me.
Mutually-assured destruction.
Exactly.
Are you gonna eat these chips?
Are you gonna
get to your point?
You need people to like you.
I don't care
if people like me.
Yes, but you need
people to like you
because you need people.
Unless you think you can get
the next court order yourself.
If Stacy can't trust you,
you can't use her.
And, that's not even
dealing with the greater
agenda of getting her
to dump her husband
and fall in love with you
all over again.
Dr. BRUCE: We were gonna be
with each other forever!
Look, I know
you're friends with her,
but there is a code.
"Bros before hoes, man."
(BEEPlNG)
Crap.
What is it?
Death row guy is dying.
(BEEPlNG)
Bradycardia. His heart rate's
dropped to 30.
It's not gonna hold out
much longer.
You just waiting to call
time of death, or are you
gonna give him atropine?
Temporary fix.
Right.
Don't know why those diabetics
are all hung up on insulin.
They're just gonna
have to take more.
Atropine's only gonna
buy you a few hours.
We don't even know
what's wrong with him.
Just get out of here.
(CELL PHONE RlNGlNG)
This is Chase.
Did you beat any confessions
out of anybody?
I haven't spoken
to any inmates.
Does anybody
do their jobs anymore?
I decided Clarence's life
isn't worth risking mine for.
Appreciate your candor.
Did you even go to the prison,
or are you just out
playing polo?
I'm searching
both of Clarence's cells.
I figured
if he's on something,
it's stashed somewhere.
Unless he finished it.
Yeah, that'd be a shame.
He could have
shoved it anywhere.
There's envelopes
stacked to the ceiling,
bottles of copier toner,
boxes of rubber bands,
paper, file folders.
Call it off.
Come on back.
What's going on?
You're dying.
HOUSE: A man
deserves a last drink.
You're okay.
Thanks. That means a lot.
All the tests
have been inconclusive?
Diagnostics is more
of an art than a science.
Should I be worried right now?
I work for one of the top
diagnosticians in the country.
We're pouring
all of our energy
into figuring this out.
HOUSE: I thought you convicts
knew how to drink.
You're at least
three shots behind.
Now you're four shots behind.
You better
get me the next one,
or I'm gonna kill you.
(CHUCKLES)
(BOTH LAUGHlNG)
House.
I was just waiting
for test results, I was...
Little busy right now.
Getting my drink on.
Unbelievable.
(CLARENCE EXCLAlMS)
That's the finest piece
I've seen in 10 years.
I could've hit that.
And you didn't?
Man, you're the one
that should be locked up.
Tell me something.
I've been trying
to figure this out.
Why does a guy
who's on death row
suddenly try to off himself?
I know you
drank that copier fluid.
It's not as visually dramatic
as slitting your wrists
with a homemade shiv,
but it will do the trick.
(SlGHlNG)
It just hit me
all of a sudden.
It was like,
they tell me when to eat,
when to sleep,
when to walk,
when to talk, everything.
I had to take
control of something, right?
When to die.
I figured that was
as good as anything.
And that thought
just came to you,
just like that?
Man, I told you,
for 23 hours...
(EXCLAlMlNG)
Look, here's the good news.
The copier fluid you drank
contains about 90% methanol,
which is very poisonous,
and you took more than enough
to kill yourself.
The bad news is,
the alcohol you just drank
contains so much ethanol that
it's going to bind with that
nasty formic acid
rampaging through your body,
hence you're just
gonna pee it out.
Harmlessly.
(CHUCKLES)
Man, you are drunk.
Yes, I am.
I also saved your life.
At least for now.
(LAUGHlNG)
(WOMAN CHATTERINN
ON P.A. SYSTEM)
Morning! Your head hurts?
No, you just have
a very grating voice.
You always were a lightweight.
Why are you talking to me?
Can't it be enough that
I wanna cause you pain?
The patient's okay now,
you're gonna send him back?
Absolutely.
Can I trust you?
You used to.
I still think
the patient's sick.
I'm keeping him here.
Yeah. Either you can
do your job and keep
the hospital informed,
or you can help me make sure
the hospital is not informed
and buy me some time.
CHASE: Have you done a CT?
Yeah, I have.
With contrast?
She's done everything
she needs to do except tell
her patient that she's dying.
I told you,
only I get to play
with the markers.
Our prisoner
has a new symptom.
I'm not telling Cindy
she's dying until the
diagnosis is confirmed.
I'm not buying that Clarence
was trying to take control
of his life by suicide.
Healthy people
don't kill themselves.
don't kill other people.
Guy just filed an appeal
in a state that hasn't
actually killed anybody
in about 30 years.
What if it wasn't suicide?
What if it was an escape plan?
Drink enough methanol to get
transferred to a hospital,
try to escape from here.
Excellent.
Explains everything
except the symptom
that got him here.
His heart went nuts
before he got stuck
in that storage cell
and chugged a toner martini.
I think there's something
going on in his head.
Check for intracranial
lesions, brain infections,
autoimmune diseases,
do a CT, LP, full workup.
State's paying, so go nuts.
FOREMAN: Where'd you
get these scars?
I got shivved
my first month in. After l
healed up, I got mines.
You guys still think I'm sick?
Obviously.
Why do you care?
Why don't you just let me die?
Well, I'm different than you.
Right. You love me
like your own mama.
That's why the nurse says
you kicked her out when
my heart nearly stopped.
Take a deep breath.
(GROANS)
Any family history
of mental illness?
I always heard
my pop was crazy,
I never met the man.
With my mom,
it was the drugs.
Any siblings?
I got a brother, pretty much
raised him on my own.
Inspirational story.
He doing time, too?
Hey...
He's a good kid.
Don't go judging
what you don't know.
How's his health?
I haven't heard from him
since I went inside.
Spent 16 years with him,
changed his damn diapers.
Can you imagine
your whole life
being all about
the worst thing you ever did?
You killed four people.
And somehow
making mac and cheese
just the way he wants
kind of loses
its significance.
Oh, no. Now you've left
your entire body in my chair.
What does that mean you want?
I need a segmental
bronchoalveolar lavage.
I take it the CT
with contrast came back?
They're not definitive.
Biopsy would be.
Biopsy would be
invasive and unnecessary.
And definitive.
But you don't want definitive,
you want to hang onto
your delusions
as long as you can.
A lavage could prove
it's not cancer.
But you need me
to approve the procedure.
Must be a bitch.
The answer is no.
Why?
Because it's me?
I'm over you!
I've jumped on the bandwagon.
And I hate you, okay?
Great. Let's treat her.
What is it?
You won't help Cindy,
but you're obsessed
with this piece of dirt!
Are you just trying to prove
that who someone
is doesn't matter,
or that all that matters
is your stupid puzzle?
Fine.
Treat them the same,
that's all I'm asking.
One test.
Wow.
That is remarkable.
According to those patchouli
oil-selling New Agers,
it's supposed to be
the terminal patient,
but you're going through
the five stages.
You just made
a completely seamless
transition from anger
to bargaining.
Cover two more
of my clinic hours,
and you can have
your one procedure.
No lesions, no aneurysms.
Ironically,
the mind of a killer
looks completely normal.
If someone asked you
to describe me to them,
what's the first thing
you'd tell them?
Insecure.
What are you asking?
Like if you were setting me up
on a blind date.
Would you describe me
to the girl as the black guy?
A neurologist?
Car thief?
This guy's really
getting to you, isn't he?
There's no sign of infection.
You're gonna
have to do the biopsy.
CUDDY: Your death row
guy's still here.
Yeah, sorry. I've just gotta
get him stabilized.
Probably keep him on fluids
for a few more hours,
then off he goes.
Oh, yeah?
'Cause I'm figuring that
you still think he's sick.
Figuring requires deductive
reasoning. I'm figuring
that you did no figuring.
Stacy just ratted me out,
right? So much for
attorney-client privilege.
I'm the client, you moron.
Stacy has a duty
to this hospital.
Right.
I'm sending him
back to prison.
Can't. Court order.
Court order says he has to be
declared healthy.
Doesn't specify
which doctor needs
to make that declaration.
(CLARENCE SCREAMlNG)
What is it, Clarence?
My gut!
Would you describe it
as a shooting pain?
A throbbing pain?
Or maybe an imaginary pain
because you don't want
to go back to prison?
Where does it hurt?
My gut, I feel like
I'm getting stabbed!
Well, he'd know.
Let me take a look.
Oh, so everybody lies
except a convicted murderer?
I don't think
he's faking this stuff.
What do you think, Doctor?
(CLARENCE GROANlNG)
I didn't have any choice.
No, you had to tell Cuddy.
She's your boss, I get it.
Hitler thought he was doing
the world a favor, too.
Yeah, pretty much
on that same level.
Gandhi didn't march to the sea
because his buddies
asked him to.
Pol Pot didn't wipe out
the teachers because he
wanted to make friends.
You're not
making friends right now.
I trusted you.
I know.
Wilson's a fool. I'm an idiot.
I had to do
what I thought was right.
It's the only reason
anybody does anything.
Surgery went fine.
They removed almost
a foot of necrotic bowel.
They're shackling him
and taking him into recovery.
I wonder.
I wonder why Clarence killed
that second inmate?
Fine, I'll bite.
What the hell
are you talking about?
Everything we do
is dictated by motive.
Why did he kill
his girlfriend?
Because he's a maniac!
Is that the reason he gave?
She was cheating on him.
Jealousy.
That gets him sent to prison.
Where he kills
inmate number one. Why?
Guy attacked him first.
Revenge.
Who'd he kill after that?
Prison guard.
Who had a file
full of abuse complaints.
Probably been kicking
Clarence's ass for months.
Clarence is just ridding
the world of bad seeds.
We'll call that one
retribution.
Then he kills
inmate number two.
Anybody know why?
Uh-uh.
It's not in there.
CLARENCE: All of a sudden,
I gotta have a reason?
It's an anomaly.
Doctors love anomalies.
Dark spot on an x-ray,
bright spot on an MRl.
Killing that second inmate
was the homicidal equivalent
of blood in the urine.
It doesn't fit.
I'm interested in things
that don't fit.
Tell me why you did it.
Your other victims
you were almost
bragging about.
What was different
about this guy?
It happened
when I was in gen pop.
I was in the library,
just reading.
And I started feeling
real nervous.
This guy was staring at me.
I could feel his eyes
digging holes
in the back of my neck.
Made me feel crazy.
Sweat was
pouring down my face.
I could hear my heartbeat
racing in my ears.
I just raged out on the dude.
So what's the differential
for raging out?
Excess testosterone, steroids.
Adrenalin?
Prep Clarence for surgery.
Care to share with the class?
Oh, come on,
do I have to spell it out
for you? Pheochromocytoma.
Actually, I'm not sure
how you spell it.
But you said it yourself,
adrenalin.
Pheochromocytoma sits on top
of the adrenal gland,
randomly spits out
oodles of the stuff.
It's perfect.
It explains everything, the
tachycardia, pulmonary edema,
the vasoconstriction that
caused the necrotic bowel.
Even explains
how he had the strength
to rip the rail off his bed.
But pheo's extremely rare.
I love rare.
Set up an MRl.
Where's Cameron?
Like I don't know.
(WOMAN LAUGHlNG)
(BOTH CHATTERlNG)
Dr. Cameron, could l
borrow you for a consult?
Bittersweet thing
about being head
of the Oncology Department,
I get cc'd on all
the biopsy results.
Yeah, I know.
She's terminal.
Yeah.
So I take it you were
in there informing her?
Well, I hadn't exactly
gotten around to that,
but I was just...
Doing what? Making friends?
Cindy's divorced.
She doesn't have any kids,
no siblings,
both her parents are gone...
It's not your job
to be her friend!
Do you understand?
And it's not worth it.
She feels better her final
few days, and you're not
the same, maybe for years.
You don't think it's worth it?
I know it's not worth it.
My husband...
I met him just after
he was diagnosed
with terminal brain cancer.
If I hadn't married him...
He was alone.
When a good person dies,
there should be an impact
on the world.
Somebody should notice.
Somebody should be upset.
"Pheo" what?
I don't even remember.
It's just a fancy way
of saying "small,
adrenalin-secreting tumor."
Yeah,
that clarified it for you.
All you need to know is,
if I'm right, we can fix it.
Just gotta find it first.
We need an MRl.
It's completely painless
for most people.
But not for me?
I assume you got
those tattoos in prison.
Prison tats often contain
inks with heavy metals.
The MRl is basically
a giant magnet,
suck those metallic inks
right out of your skin.
(GROANlNG)
(SCREAMlNG)
Stop squirming.
Don't make us do this again.
Big baby.
Still don't see anything.
(CLARENCE GROANlNG)
CLARENCE: Turn it off!
There's Waldo.
Found it, Clarence.
Turn it off!
Turn this damn thing off!
Keep him in there
until you guys see it, too.
Son of a bitch.
Looks like they got
the pheo out successfully.
So, what now?
Clarence goes back
to death row.
Just like that?
He's cured.
That tumor caused
random shots of adrenalin,
which obviously led
to the rage attacks that
made him become a murderer
in the first place.
My God, you're right!
Let's call the surgeons,
we gotta save that tumor.
Put it on the witness stand.
We could testify
at Clarence's appeal.
You smell that?
I think that is the stink
of hypocrisy.
You wouldn't even consider
the notion that Clarence's
social upbringing
was responsible for what
he became, but now you're
sprinting to the witness stand
to blame everything
on a little tumor.
A person's upbringing
and their biology
are completely different.
Yeah.
Because you only
overcame one of them.
Well, let's just
give Clarence a free pass.
Which is probably
gonna piss off all those
other pheo sufferers
who managed to control
their rage attacks
and become lawyers,
race car drivers,
or even doctors.
Removing that tumor
puts a stop to those
random shots of adrenalin.
It doesn't absolve him.
You want him to be executed?
That's not what I'm saying.
Got an opinion?
Everyone's got an opinion.
I... I think I'm gonna testify
at Clarence's appeal.
You'll do
what you think is right.
On your own time.
But it's just a cough.
www.tvsubtitles.net